{
    "id": "cc5a2517d6fe429f84c28876441e566c",
    "title": "Conditional Clauses Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "If you had applied in time, you …………………………… the job.",
            "description": "In the third conditional, use a past perfect tense in the if-clause and would/could/might have + past participle in the main clause. ",
            "answers": [
                "will get",
                "would get",
                "would have got"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "4883f799256c4c438f64fa63d91bbd0f"
        },
        {
            "question": "If she arrived now, we …………………………. ask her.",
            "description": "In the second conditional, use a simple past in the if-clause and would + first form of the verb in the main clause. ",
            "answers": [
                "can",
                "could",
                "could have"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "1ff9777e090d40fdabe2bb477407a4a0"
        },
        {
            "question": "If it ……………………………., the program will be postponed.",
            "description": "In the first conditional, use a simple present tense in the if clause and will/can/may + first form of the verb in the main clause. ",
            "answers": [
                "rains",
                "rained",
                "had rained"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "c9db399d3cc0459d99219c1c049b214a"
        },
        {
            "question": "If I ………………………… your wallet, I will give it to you.",
            "description": "In the first conditional, use a simple present tense in the if clause and will/can/may + first form of the verb in the main clause. ",
            "answers": [
                "find",
                "found",
                "had found"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "3341317953394a5692dd5a033036dfef"
        },
        {
            "question": "If you tease the dog, it ………………………….. bite you.",
            "description": "In the first conditional, use a simple present tense in the if clause and will/can/may + first form of the verb in the main clause. ",
            "answers": [
                "will",
                "would",
                "would have"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "2916e58fd815494eb6cde411f942db5d"
        },
        {
            "question": "If she had learned her lesson, she ……………………………. this.",
            "description": "In the third conditional, use a past perfect tense in the if-clause and would/could/might have + past participle in the main clause. ",
            "answers": [
                "will not repeat",
                "would not have repeated",
                "would not repeat"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "70bb28eb4823446b8e375d52bfd4b556"
        },
        {
            "question": "If I …………………………. guests, I cannot come with you.",
            "description": "In the first conditional, use a simple present tense in the if clause and will/can/may + first form of the verb in the main clause. ",
            "answers": [
                "have",
                "had",
                "have had"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "f4c00034ab154e06a264589a2e623b12"
        },
        {
            "question": "If you gave up now, it ………………………….. a disgrace.",
            "description": "In the second conditional, use a simple past in the if-clause and would/could/might + first form of the verb in the main clause. ",
            "answers": [
                "will be",
                "would be",
                "would have been"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "377ef9b156974620a0a7d213ad7e1336"
        },
        {
            "question": "If I ………………………….. you, I wouldn’t invest in that company.",
            "description": "In the second conditional, use a simple past in the if-clause and would/could/might + first form of the verb in the main clause. ",
            "answers": [
                "am",
                "were",
                "had been"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "a4db672f1fe0485fa343e70c1f951d1e"
        },
        {
            "question": "If you …………………………. smoking, your health would improve.",
            "description": "In the second conditional, use a simple past in the if-clause and would/could/might + first form of the verb in the main clause. ",
            "answers": [
                "stop",
                "stopped",
                "had stopped"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "139f317ea72a4237aff86cec670b5c0a"
        },
        {
            "question": "If you ………………………. a degree, you would get a better job.",
            "description": "In the second conditional, use a simple past in the if-clause and would/could/might + first form of the verb in the main clause. ",
            "answers": [
                "have",
                "had",
                "have had"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "a8f1981ec13146ef80f3f830a5088fe2"
        },
        {
            "question": "If you ………………………….. again, you would have succeeded.",
            "description": "In the third conditional, use a past perfect tense in the if-clause and would/could/might have + past participle in the main clause. ",
            "answers": [
                "try",
                "tried",
                "had tried"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "9e443cb5c28b4c2a8ce83866ed0f6451"
        }
    ]
}